now we are going to see how we can do
different folder operations using the
kbox automation modules
so let's create another test folder here
called folder operations where we'll
create all our test cases
inside this let's create our first test
case
which is to create a folder okay
so let's create this test case and let's
quickly add our
ebox module so we'll call it t-box and
create
okay so that will
appear as the Box create module or the
Box create folder module okay and we
have to give a path here
so we'll use the same folder which we
have been using for our testing
so this is the c training folder and in
override will set it to true
but in the part I need to extend it so
that I can create a subfolder inside
that particular folder right otherwise
it's going to just overwrite that
particular folder
so I'm going to call it folder one
and let's quickly run this
okay so a new folder should be created
here as you can see in this particular
training folder there is a folder one
okay
there is no files obviously but there is
a new folder
so our next operation folder operation
is to copy a particular folder okay
so let's say t-box or let's call it copy
folder
so let's add the module here quickly so
we are going to search for t-box and
copy
right so there are two modules copy file
and copy folder we are going to use copy
folder here we are going to give the
source path
so our source path will be c training
right
let's copy this folder into somewhere
else okay and I will probably use the
other folder which I've been using which
is the C samples
so I'll copy this here as a subfolder
right I can give the over right as true
and let's go ahead and quickly run this
okay so as you can see uh the contents
of uh the training folder are now copied
into the samples
okay so the folder one is created or
copied and the files are also copied
right
so that's how you can copy
um a folder and its content from One
path to another path okay
and let's go to our third operation now
so let's create a new test case here
and we are going to call it to delete a
folder okay so we'll see how we can
delete a folder
and inside this again let's add our
module so t-box delete
and we are going to select folder
okay so it is asking for a path again
give the path where you want to delete
this so
let's go ahead and delete this folder
one okay
and um if you want to delete everything
inside that particular folder right so
you can also give the recursive value as
true okay so we don't have any files
inside inside folder one but if we have
and if it is set to true then it will
delete everything okay otherwise it
won't delete anything inside the folder
one
so uh let's go ahead and run this
okay so let's go to the c training
folder and there should not be any
folder one because we have deleted it
okay
right
um so what we are going to do
is we are going to check for our final
folder operation so that is to
check for a folder existence Okay so
check
folder existence now this could be a
interesting one because this could be a
common one which you will use probably
to check a particular folder is present
maybe a reports folder or some test data
folder before you run your test cases
right so this could be a useful one for
that let's go ahead and add the t-box
module so check
or it could be
t-box folder existence okay
so this is the module and here we just
need to give the path of the folder
which we want to verify right
and that will just verify it okay
so uh I think you cannot browse it so
let's go ahead and give this particular
path okay
and let's go ahead and run this
so the verification has passed uh
verification was successful as usual it
will give you an expected and actual
value folder does exist expected value
was this right should exist
so this is uh in scenarios where you
want to check uh whether that folder
exists before any performing any
operations in that right so what you can
also do is basically have this test case
right inside uh or the first test case
in your folder operations okay
so first you verify then you create
right or and then you copy and then you
delete
what you can also do you can put if
condition and put all this into one
particular test case if you want to run
through one test case with all different
steps right so that also you can do but
these are the different uh t-box
automation modules which you can use for
different folder operations and as we
have seen earlier you can also use them
for file operations okay